<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-02-15T02:49:26-08:00</updated><id>https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles//</id><title type="html">sneaky scribbles</title><subtitle>this is a blog full of various articles about web development, programming, and even a few personal things. it's a dedicated blog by Zachary E Sohovich</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Plans for sneakycr0w.com</title><link href="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/02/09/sneakycr0w-plans.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plans for sneakycr0w.com" /><published>2017-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/02/09/sneakycr0w-plans</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/02/09/sneakycr0w-plans.html">&lt;p&gt;So sneakycr0w.com is going to be my personal website. I don’t plan on using it much more than showing my project list, having a little blog/scribble area, and minor updates to my resume and what not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m in the process of writing a &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/&quot;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; application for the projects section. That’s going to connect to a PostgreSQL database that’ll just contain one table with all my projects. Easy enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;scribbles&quot;&gt;Scribbles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scribbles section is simply going to be a blog. It’ll contain both personal posts as well as development. But, the &lt;em&gt;primary&lt;/em&gt; focus is going to be development, as this website is a professional one. At the same token, I don’t want it to be too formal or impersonal because that’s simply not who I am as a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to add more things to the homepage. Right now I don’t have a lot of ideas beyond changing that banner image and adding a “buy me a coffee” panel/link, haha. I want to incorporate stripe so I can better maneuver with it, so I thought that would be a great  way to learn the API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to repeat that this blog is going to be a bunch of scribbles. Some posts are going to be long, some super short. It’s basically a notebook of my mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">So sneakycr0w.com is going to be my personal website. I don’t plan on using it much more than showing my project list, having a little blog/scribble area, and minor updates to my resume and what not.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I started developing</title><link href="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/01/01/how-I-started-developing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I started developing" /><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/01/01/how-I-started-developing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sneakycr0w.com//scribbles/personal/2017/01/01/how-I-started-developing.html">&lt;p&gt;So, at the time I’m writing this, it’s about midnight. I’m a bit tired, and I totally forgot that I mentioned I would make another post before I went to bed. But, this blog I’m going to stick by my promise to be active. Unfortunately, I can’t write my whole about me section tonight, so this will have to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-start-of-a-legend&quot;&gt;The Start of a Legend&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the age of 12 I was only into computers as much as everyone else. I thought the idea was cool, but not nearly as much as I do now that I have more of a grasp on them. Aside from the “family computer” I didn’t own a computer. That was until the age of age of 12 when I got my first computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother’s bosses son was studying computer science and my mom asked him if he could come setup my computer for me. So, while he was in my room setting it up I, being the curious little scamp that I am, asked him loads of questions. The more I asked him the more interested I got. At this age, I was still into video games a lot. I had heard about how much better PC Gaming was at the time (although I wouldn’t feel the true power of a gaming PC until I was about 20), but he made it sound even better. He got me started on my very first PC game which I would play for the next 10 years, which was Wolfenstein: Enemy Territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game was the first game’s I experienced what a true community felt like. I made friends, I joined clans (just groups of gamers with similar interests), and participated in a bunch of community events. Eventually, I became more interested in starting my own groups. So a bunch of friends and I decided we wanted to get a server, make a website, and start our own group. The only problem was, none of us knew how to do any of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server was easy, they had websites that you could rent and you could set them up without ever touching the command line. But, you did have to touch the configuration files and if you wanted to get crazy you would have to do some scripting. So I rented our first server, set up some basic stuff on it, and got it running. We still didn’t have a website though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;enter-coding&quot;&gt;Enter coding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I was one to do my research. And, while googling “how to make a website” all the “good” tutorials always seemed to want me to use Photoshop. At this age, I had no way of grabbing that program (or at least no knowledge of how to get it anyway), so I resorted to alternative methods. One of which was learning through pure code. I started with HTML, learned CSS, and made some basic websites. Honestly, that wasn’t going to cut it for the purpose of the website. So I used a few CMS, and then modified them as I saw fit. Eventually, this led me to learning PHP and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I stopped playing as much video games and did more for the groups ironically. So in a way I was still playing, but become more known for helping groups modify their servers as well as their websites. Eventually, I realized that coding is what I loved doing, and I started teaching myself different languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the story of how I started coding!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;note-maybe-for-the-next-few-posts-ill-just-post-a-little-bit-more-about-me-here-and-there-as-well-as-development-posts-i-want-this-blog-not-just-to-be-professional-but-personal-too&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Maybe for the next few posts I’ll just post a little bit more about me here and there as well as development posts. I want this blog not just to be professional but personal too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;</content><summary type="html">So, at the time I’m writing this, it’s about midnight. I’m a bit tired, and I totally forgot that I mentioned I would make another post before I went to bed. But, this blog I’m going to stick by my promise to be active. Unfortunately, I can’t write my whole about me section tonight, so this will have to suffice.</summary></entry></feed>
